Fernando José Delgado Quintana

Phone: 787.587.0590 • E-Mail: fernandojose@icloud.com • Portfolio: www.fjdqdesigns.com



Profile

Professional with extensive technical skills. Excellent communicator, experienced in understanding and implementing client and staff vision of new projects. Prospers in environments that constantly embrace new technologies. I love what I do and always give 100%. When I take on a project, I go the extra mile and make it better than requested. Fluent in both English and Spanish.

Skills

Programming: Java, C++, VB, PHP, HTML, CSS, JS, Python, JQuery, Ionic, Git, and AngularJS **Software:** CMS (Joomla, WordPress), Adobe Creative Suite, iWork, and Microsoft Office

Database: Oracle, SQL, MySQL

Operating Systems: Windows, Macintosh, Linux

Experience

Speak Agent August 2015 – Present

Web Developer: Remote Front-End development working in AngularJS and Ionic for start-up in Rockville, Maryland.

Seattle University March 2015 – August 2016

Professor of Web Development: Working on multiple hybrid courses. Course included: Intro to HTML, CSS, JS and Intro to Servers and Hosting. Prepare online videos each week, and worked with students to clear doubts.

Colegio San José August 2012 – May 2015

Professor: Alice, and Python in 10th grade. Java in 11th grade, and Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, and Visual Basic in 12th grade.

FJDQ Designs July 2011 – Present

Freelance: web developer managing client relationships, budgets, and designing websites with responsive layouts. Developed secure web sites and back-end administrative panel for start-up companies. Hired to develop content management system for school, non-profit organizations, doctors, and car custom shop.

Web Satisfaction February 2011 – February 2013

CSS Specialist: Developed and maintained clients Internet web sites. Designed online marketing solutions, applications, and blogs. Provided maintenance and support for our clients.

Education

M.E., Computer Engineering
Polytechnic University of Puerto Rico

August 2012 - May 2014

B.S., Computer Science University of Puerto Rico, Bayamón Campus August 2007 – May 2012

Awards

2004 Water Polo National Team First Place Medal in the Caribbean Island Swimming Championships in Jamaica 2005 National Youth Technology Forum Nominee

2005 Water Polo National Team Second Place Medal in the Centroamericanos del caribe afiliado a natacion in Santo Domingo

2009 Water Polo National Team First Place Medal in the Centroamericanos del caribe afiliado a natacion in Venezuela